We did it. We've covered so much CSS and you're doing great.
你做到了 我们学习了很多 CSS 知识 你完成得很棒
We've talked about how CSS selectors, classes, and IDs,
我们了解了 CSS 选择器 类名 ID 等等
we've discussed inline CSS plus external style sheets,
我们也讨论了内联 CSS 样式和外部样式表
we've talked about setting CSS rules for different properties like color,
以及设置不同的 CSS 属性来应用不同的 CSS 规则
and border, and so much more.
比如 颜色 边框 等等
But believe it or not,
信不信由你
there's even more that can be done with CSS.
CSS 还有很多能完成的事情
I thought I would use this time just to show you a couple additional CSS tips and tricks.
在这里我会花一些时间向你展示一些额外的 CSS 小技巧
So if we look here,
看看这里
we have our boxes that were used to alphabet beats coincidental drums,
我们有一些 box 元素：alphabet、beats、coincidental、drums
here are my CSS rules setup for box.
这里是对应的 CSS 规则
Now, there's a couple of things I want to try here.
我想在这里做一些改变
One is border radius which has rounded corners.
首先是使用 border radius 来增加圆角效果
This is one of my favorite emergent styles in the web development world I'd say.
这是 web 开发中我最喜欢的一个新兴样式之一
It's been a couple of years now,
它出现有几年了
but people are really starting to take advantage of the fact that we don't need
但是实际上人们很少意识到
all those rectangles to just be crisp lines.
并不一定所有的矩形都需要是清晰的直角线条
I think it adds a lot of style to set a little bit depart on a border-radius.
不遵循传统 而是使用 border-radius 之后 可以好看很多
So here's one way.
所以
To do border-radius we can setup with the border-radius name,
为了改变边框半径 我们可以设置 border-radius
and then we could just say 25 Px,
然后设置为 25px
which as you see bend these corners a bit,
你可以看到边角已经变圆润了一些
but then we lose our words.
不过一部分文字被挡住了
So what we can do to ameliorate that is
为了解决这个问题
to just add a little padding as well with the border-radius.
我们可以同时添加一些内边距
Now we can see we have our smooth corners and we're not losing our words.
现在我们已经有了平滑的边角 文字也没有没挡住
Border-radius can also take percentages.
border-radius 也可以采用百分比的方式
For example, let's see what happens when we do border-radius 45 percent.
比如 我们可以看看设置为百分之 45 会发生什么
Wow, things got circular.
Wow 它变成了环形的
What about 85 percent?
如果是百分之 85 呢 ?
Cool.
很酷
You can start to see by playing around the different shapes and
只需要通过使用 border-radius 你就可以
setups you can make just using border-radius.
开始拥有不同形状的元素
So what if we wanted instead of
那么 如果除了这些单词之外
those just those words to have a background image in each of these circles?
我想在这些圆形区域内添加一些图片呢？
That's something we can also do easily with CSS.
我们也可以通过 CSS 轻易做到
So here in the box,
在 box 内部
what I'm going to do is I'm going to use the background image property which takes URL,
我们要做的就是使用背景图片属性 它需要一个 URL
it's the path to the image we want which happens to be the name this time as well.
来指明我们的图片来源 这里正好就是图片名称
You can see over here on my folder,
你可以在文件夹里看到
I have the image demo.jpg,
我们有一个 demo.jpg 的图片
so here I give it the URL I want,
所以这里我们设置好我们想要的图片
and then I'm going to set background size to cover.
然后设置背景大小为 cover
I'll show you in a sec but the background size can do when we change it up.
当我们改变背景大小的时候我会再向你展示它能做什么
But let's take a look at this.
但是我们先看一看这个
You see now that the image that I have has been placed as
可以看到我们设置的背景图片
the background for all of these images including with the border-radius that I set.
全部都生效了 同时包括之前设置的 border-radius 属性
So what would happen if I instead of cover tried contained?
如果我把 cover 改为 contain 会发生什么情况呢 ?
Now, you can see what's happened is it has taken the picture and
你可以看到背景图片重复了多次
it's putting it over multiple times to fill up this space that's there.
来填充满整个空间
Playing with the background size can give you incredible amount of
通过使用背景尺寸属性 你可以有多种自定义的方式
detail oriented customization over just how your images and image background look.
来决定你的背景图片如何显示
I like this here.
我喜欢这一点
I would like to see the words a tiny bit bigger.
我也想要这些单词变大一些
So I might bring it all together and say,
所以我们来设置字体大小为
''That's a great spelling error example like 67 pixels.
这是一个很好的拼写错误例子 67 像素
Now we're talking.''
好了
These are just a few more of the things you can do with CSS.
这就是一些更多关于 CSS 的技巧
I hope this is opening up your mind,
希望能够给你带来一些灵感
and focusing your intelligence and your imagination into
并利用你的脑洞和想象力
all the possibilities that can be created with HTML and CSS. Good luck.最新课程跟课件还有一对一辅导请加wx：udacity6
用 HTML 和 CSS 做一些有趣的事情 祝你好运。最新课程跟课件还有一对一辅导请加wx：udacity6